<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Robert Grunsky</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Robert Grunsky</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Using Windows for Everything</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/using_windows/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/using_windows/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/uploads/windows.png" alt="Featured image of post Using Windows for Everything" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-windows-for-everything&#34;&gt;Using Windows for &lt;em&gt;Everything&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course the past 15 years, dual booting was a mainstay in my lifestyle. I used a MacBook pro for my creative work such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/djrov9/rov9-init-mix&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DJing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://younginfinity.bandcamp.com/album/geode&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;music creation&lt;/a&gt;, and kept the gaming on my windows desktop, and most of the tinkering on a separate partition with Fedora Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time however, the setup began to show its age. Not only was my hardware becoming outdated, but it also turns out I would spend time working on a project in Linux land, then I would be sidetracked by some new game I wanted to play in Windows, and finally I would spend a couple months making strides on some musical endeavors using my Mac. In other words, I would move from system to system, rarely finishing projects, and having difficulty keeping track of where I left off when I would return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed to me that the best solution would be all-in-one. As opposed to using three different operating systems for all the tasks I set out to do, it seemed to me that a single, powerful computer would be perfectly sufficient for all my needs. This time though, there would be no dual booting. I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to settle on a single operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uploads/ScreenshotWindows.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Windows doing it all.&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-windows&#34;&gt;Why Windows?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been dual booting Linux on all my Windows Machines since 2003. I truly wanted to be all in with Linux. UNIX filesystems, the gnu toolchain, the beauty of the shell. Everything from the freedom of open source and libre philosophy to the way it all worked, I was a true believer. But I wanted to play games. Not to mention music. And&amp;hellip; oh never mind. Linux never became the definitive operating system that I wanted it  to be for me. The audio latency and driver issues, the graphic drivers issues (looking at you NVIDIA), the anti-cheat issues, and so on and so forth. For this all-in-one project it just won&amp;rsquo;t do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I certainly considered mac, but one of my goals was to be able to change out parts as needed so I wanted to use some parts from my last PC in order to save money. Since I can&amp;rsquo;t build my own Mac (officially, that is) I chose Windows as the Operating System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-discovered&#34;&gt;What I Discovered
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After using Windows exclusively for a little over a year, I&amp;rsquo;ve come away mighty impressed. There have been improvements to every aspect of the experience since the days of yore. Windows can be tiled, the powershell has been upgraded to be an extremely powerful experience nearly on par with its linux equivalents, it has package managers such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://scoop.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;scoop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;, and I even have my favorite text editor &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://neovim.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;neovim&lt;/a&gt;. Running git, testing my hugo pages, and using VScode all has integrated into my windows usage with minimal learning curve, and I am here for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the audio side of my life, Windows is unable to match the utter brilliance of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/coreaudio&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Core Audio&lt;/a&gt;. However, Windows stands head and shoulders above my experience with Linux. Fighting the issues running my favorite plugins, issues with drivers, and issues generally all around became altogether a non-starter. Once I got the correct drivers set up in Windows, everything really became mostly seamless. I certainly ran into some baffling issues such as needing to run Ableton as administrator in order to properly prioritize the program and its plugins in order to reduce latency, and an issue where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t watch youtube videos while running audio software simultaneously. Once I solved those issues, everything truly just works. I spend the majority of my creative time &lt;em&gt;creating&lt;/em&gt;. A truly beautiful thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose I should mention gaming. while it&amp;rsquo;s certainly the least concerning issue to me, Windows just absolutely blows every other operating system out of the water in this regard. When I want to play a game, my good old Radeon RX 580 is still giving me plenty of leg room. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to throw a game at it that just won&amp;rsquo;t run (with the glaring exception of Gothic II. What gives?!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uploads/gothicviolation.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My favorite part of Gothic 2&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so many aspects of this I still want to touch on, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/about&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ikmultimedia.com/products/amplitube5/index.php&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;amp sims for guitar&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save those for the future. Most of my activities have been able to be relegated to a single corner in my living room, which has been vital since I no longer have a designated office space. Having the PC in one place, ready to go for every project I throw at it has helped keep things focused in a way I haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced before. In conclusion, using one Windows PC for all my activities this year has proven to be a very fruitful endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Problem of Starting</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/blog/starting/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/blog/starting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/uploads/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Problem of Starting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://popeye.fandom.com/wiki/J._Wellington_Wimpy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uploads/wimpy3.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;J. Wellington Wimpy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting something new. A new beginning or starting over. Sometimes it’s triggered by a desire
to begin a new project, or we set a new goal, and other times we face it because
of hard drive failure or a divorce. The funny thing about starting is that it’s
a problem that’s as old as time. There are so many excuses not to start. Some might
say &amp;ldquo;never put off till tomorrow what you can do the day after tomorrow,&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://quoteinvestigator.com/2013/01/17/put-off/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;as stated by Mark Twaine, or Oscar Wilde, or someone like that.&lt;/a&gt;
and others may just be avoiding making payments, not unlike &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._Wellington_Wimpy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;J. Wellington Wimpy&lt;/a&gt;.
If creating something from nothing requires a grandiose god to accomplish such a
feat, how is a mere mortal expected to do the same?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://little-scale.blogspot.com/2012/05/my-adayorg-photoset.html?m=0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uploads/image4t.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;NAH&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve described some situations where we might have to start &lt;em&gt;something.&lt;/em&gt; The first few
issues raised when I’m faced with the problem of starting tend to be: Do I have
the materials I need? E.g. Do I have the money? Do I have the equipment? Once I
can confirm that I have at least the minimum amount of what I need, do I have the
skills? And if I have the skills, do I have a plan? And if I have a plan and I have
the skills, do I have the time? And if I have the plan, I have the skills, and I
have the time and I have what I need but I still don’t have the mechanical keyboard
that I want, then maybe I should spend a few hours on amazon lusting over the best
option because it’s just got to be the best, and it turns out I can’t afford it
but now I don’t have time, so I better put it off until tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tomorrow-never-comes&#34;&gt;Tomorrow Never Comes
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s true. The mythical tomorrow truly never comes. Any time we procrastinate,
there’s a ripple effect that resonates far and wide throughout our lives. Dreams
unfulfilled, business not dealt, promises broken, pride, self-worth, and trustworthiness
diminished. These reasons and more are some strong arguments for starting. It’s
never going to be done until it’s begun. So, I’ve decided to begin. But does it
live up to my expectations? Could it be better? Maybe I should throw it out. I’ve
just hit possibly the biggest hurdle in my journey of creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;perfectionism&#34;&gt;Perfectionism
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;At last I’ve started. The formless is beginning to take shape. Projects are closing
in on the finish lines and debts are being snowballed. But I can’t publish. I give
up half way through, another Ableton session never to be opened again. It just didn’t
work out, and even if it could be worked out, I don’t have the time, the skills,
the tools, nor do I have a plan. This is the dark place, and there is no lantern
to light the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pexels.com/photo/grayscale-photography-of-naked-person-sitting-on-the-floor-with-his-head-bent-to-his-knees-in-a-dark-place-2930186/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uploads/image2.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Grayscale Photography of Naked Person Sitting On The Floor With His Head Bent To His Knees In A Dark Place&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does one &amp;quot;un-stuck&amp;quot; themselves from this rut? Perhaps the best solution is
just to start, start again, and somehow yet again. Do I simply keep drinking from
that immaterial substance that brought the big bang of initial inspiration, or do
I wait for a new cow to arrive from a pasture unknown?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-truth-hurts&#34;&gt;The Truth Hurts
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never going to be perfect. Nothing done in this life is ever going to be perfect.
Like building sandcastles, eventually all will be broken down by the waves of the
ocean of life itself. No matter how much effort put in or planning that’s been done,
there can always be better. How can I be happy with the final result? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.psychologistworld.com/cognitive/maximizers-satisficers-decision-making&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;I’m a maximizer,
not a satisficer&lt;/a&gt;,
and I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; it could be better. This sentiment has been shared with nearly all
creators the world over, but at some point, one just has to stop, give it the seal
of approval, and move on to another new project and start the whole process over
again. Or perhaps I’ll put it off today and just wait until tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
